Tej Chajed

Curriculum Vitae

☎ +1 (217) 840-0140 ⋈ tchajed@mit.edu 1 https://chajed.io

Research Interests

I work on formal verification for systems software. In my research I develop **realistic**, **performant systems**, specify their intended behavior, then prove that the implementation always meet the specification. So far my research has focused on developing a **verified file system** that is concurrent, protects your data even if the computer suddenly reboots, and gets good performance.

Education

2014–2021 Ph.D. in Computer Science, MIT, Cambridge, MA.

(expected) Verifying a concurrent, crash-safe file system with sequential reasoning

2014–2017 M.S. in Computer Science, GPA: 4.0/4.0, MIT, Cambridge, MA. Verifying an I/O-concurrent file system

2010–2014 **B.S. in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science**, GPA: 3.97/4.0, University of Illinois, Urbana, IL.

Research Experiences

2014–present **Research assistant**, at MIT in the PDOS group. advised by Frans Kaashoek and Nickolai Zeldovich

2013–2014 **Undergraduate researcher**, at University of Illinois in the DPRG group. advised by Indranil Gupta

Draft papers

draft 2021 Separation logic for concurrent storage systems with Peony Joseph Tassarotti, Tej Chajed, Ralf Jung, Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich

 $\mathit{draft~2021}$ Verifying the DaisyNFS concurrent and crash-safe file system with sequential proofs

Tej Chajed, Joseph Tassarotti, Mark Theng, Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich

Conference Publications

OSDI 2021 **GoJournal: a verified, concurrent, crash-safe journaling system**Tej Chajed, Joseph Tassarotti, Mark Theng, Ralf Jung, M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich

SOSP 2019 Verifying concurrent, crash-safe systems with Perennial Tej Chajed, Joseph Tassarotti, M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich

Security 2019 EverParse: Verified Secure Zero-Copy Parsers for Authenticated **Message Formats** Tahina Ramananandro, Antoine Delignat-Lavaud, Cédric Fournet, Nikhil Swamy, Tej Chajed, Nadim Kobeissi, Jonathan Protzenko PLDI 2019 Argosy: Verifying Layered Storage Systems with Recovery Refinement Tej Chajed, Joseph Tassarotti, M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich OSDI 2018 Verifying concurrent software using movers in CSPEC Tej Chajed, M. Frans Kaashoek, Butler Lampson, and Nickolai Zeldovich OSDI 2018 Proving confidentiality in a file system using DiskSec Atalay İleri, Tej Chajed, Adam Chlipala, M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich SOSP 2017 Verifying a high-performance crash-safe file system using a tree specification Haogang Chen, Tej Chajed, Alex Konradi, Stephanie Wang, Atalay İleri, Adam Chlipala, M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich SOSP 2015 Using Crash Hoare Logic for certifying the FSCQ file system Haogang Chen, Daniel Ziegler, Tej Chajed, Adam Chlipala, M. Frans Kaashoek, and Nickolai Zeldovich SoCC 2013 Natjam: design and evaluation of eviction policies for supporting priorities and deadlines in mapreduce clusters Brian Cho, Muntasir Rahman, Tej Chajed, Indranil Gupta, Cristina Abad, Nathan Roberts, Philbert Lin Workshop Papers CoqPL 2021 Record Updates in Coq Tej Chajed CoqPL 2020 Verifying concurrent Go code in Coq with Goose Tej Chajed, Joseph Tassarotti, M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich HotOS 2015 Amber: Decoupling user data from web applications Tej Chajed, Jon Gjengset, Jelle van den Hooff, M. Frans Kaashoek, James Mickens, Robert Morris, Nickolai Zeldovich Industry Experience

Teaching Experiences

2014

Fall 2020 TA, 6.826 (Principles of Computer Systems), MIT, Cambridge, MA.

Summer Research Intern, Microsoft Research, Cambridge, UK.
2017 Verifying low-level parsing in F*, with Cédric Fournet
Summer Software Engineering Intern, Google, Zurich, Switzerland.

Fall 2019 TA, 6.826 (Principles of Computer Systems), MIT, Cambridge, MA.

Fall 2017 TA, 6.826 (Principles of Computer Systems), MIT, Cambridge, MA.

Spring 2017 **Course development**, 6.826 (Principles of Computer Systems), MIT, Cambridge, MA.

I helped develop the labs for 6.826 (Principles of Computer Systems) during Spring 2017.

Honors & Awards

2014–2019 NSF Graduate Research Fellowship

2014 Jacobs Presidential Fellowship

2019–2014 Chancellor's Scholar

Professional Service

- o PLDI 2022, Program Committee
- Organized a tutorial at POPL 2021, "Iris A Modular Foundation for Higher-Order Concurrent Separation Logic"
- o EuroDW 2021 (EuroSys Doctoral Workshop), PC
- o POPL 2021, Artifact Evaluation Committee
- o PLDI 2020, Artifact Evaluation Committee
- o POPL 2020, Artifact Evaluation Committee
- o SOSP 2019, Artifact Evaluation Committee

References

- Frans Kaashoek kaashoek@mit.edu
- Nickolai Zeldovich nickolai@csail.mit.edu